{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The effective length of a compression member of length L held in position and restrained in direction at one end and effectively restrained in direction but not held in position at the other end, is", "opta": "L", "optb": "0.67 L", "optc": "0.85 L", "optd": "1.5 L", "opte": "2 L", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ratio of shearing stress to shearing strain within elastic limit, is known as", "opta": "modulus of elasticity", "optb": "shear modulus of elasticity", "optc": "bulk modulus of elasticity", "optd": "tangent modulus of elasticity", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For determination of allowable stress in axial compression, Indian Standard Institution has adopted", "opta": "Euler's formula", "optb": "Rankine formula", "optc": "Engesser formula", "optd": "Secant formula", "opte": "Perry Robertson formula.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The method of design of steel framework for greatest rigidity and economy in weight, is known as", "opta": "simply design", "optb": "semi-rigid design", "optc": "fully rigid design", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the pitch is 6 cm and rivet value is 4 tonnes, the number of rivets required for a riveted connection carrying an eccentric load of 15 tonnes at a distance of 30 cm from the centre line, is", "opta": "6", "optb": "8", "optc": "10", "optd": "12", "opte": "15", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In plastic analysis, the shape factor for circular sections, is", "opta": "1.5", "optb": "1.6", "optc": "1.697", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The critical stress on a column for elastic buckling given by Euler's formula, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A beam is defined as a structural member subjected to", "opta": "axial loading", "optb": "transverse loading", "optc": "axial and transverse loading", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "According to IS : 800 - 71, the minimum thickness of a vertically stiffened web plate, shall not be less than", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A fillet weld may be termed as", "opta": "mitre weld", "optb": "concave weld", "optc": "convex weld", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the moment of inertia of a section about its axis is I and its effective sectional area is A, its radius of gyration r about the axis, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The critical load for a column of length I hinged at both ends and having flexural rigidity El, is given by", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Slenderness ratio of a compression member is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "Vertical stiffeners may be placed in pairs one on each side of the web", "optb": "Single vertical stiffeners may be placed alternately on opposite sides of the web", "optc": "Horizontal stiffeners may be placed in pairs one on each side of the web", "optd": "Horizontal stiffeners may be placed alternately on opposite sides of the web", "opte": "All the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A structural member subjected to compressive stress in a direction parallel to its longitudinal axis, is generally known as", "opta": "column", "optb": "stanchion", "optc": "post", "optd": "strut", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The equivalent axial tensile load Pe, which produces an average axial tensile stress in the section equivalent to the combined stress due to axial tension P and bending M, at the extreme fibre of the section, is given by (where Z is the section modulus of the section).", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Live load", "opta": "varies in magnitude", "optb": "varies in position", "optc": "is expressed as uniformly distributed load", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The most economical section for a column, is", "opta": "rectangular", "optb": "solid round", "optc": "flat strip", "optd": "tubular section", "opte": "hexagonal.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the depth of two column sections are equal, then the column splice is provided", "opta": "with filler plates", "optb": "with bearing plates", "optc": "with filler and hearing plates", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The distance between e.g. of compression and e.g. of tension flanges of a plate girder, is known as", "opta": "overall depth", "optb": "clear depth", "optc": "effective depth", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Web crippling generally occurs at the point where", "opta": "bending moment is maximum", "optb": "shearing force is minimum", "optc": "concentrated loads act", "optd": "deflection is maximum", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the incorrect statement from the following:", "opta": "The nominal diameter of a rivet is its diameter before driving", "optb": "The gross diameter of a rivet is the diameter of rivet hole", "optc": "The gross area of a rivet is the cross-sectional area of the rivet hole", "optd": "The diameter of a rivet hole is equal to the nominal diameter of the rivet plus 1.5 mm", "opte": "None of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The allowable stress in axial tension for rolled I-sections and channels, is taken as", "opta": "1420 kg/cm2", "optb": "1500 kg/cm2", "optc": "2125 kg/cm2", "optd": "1810 kg/cm2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a tension member is made of four angles with a plate as a web, the allowance for holes is made as", "opta": "two holes for each angle and one hole for the web", "optb": "one hole for each angle and one hole for the web", "optc": "one hole for each angle and two holes for the web", "optd": "two holes for each angle and two holes for the web", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The failure of a web plate takes place by yielding if the ratio of the clear depth to thickness of the web, is less than", "opta": "45", "optb": "55", "optc": "60", "optd": "75", "opte": "82", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The minimum edge distance of a rivet line connecting two or more plates, is kept equal to 37 mm plus (where t is the thickness in mm of the thinner outside plate).", "opta": "2 t", "optb": "4 t", "optc": "6 t", "optd": "8 t", "opte": "10 t", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "Dead load includes self-weight of the structure and super-imposed loads permanently attached to the structure", "optb": "Dead loads change their positions and vary in magnitude", "optc": "Dead loads are known in the beginning of the design", "optd": "None of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum permissible slenderness ratio of a member carrying loads resulting from wind, is", "opta": "180", "optb": "200", "optc": "250", "optd": "300", "opte": "350", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If d is the distance between the flange angles, the vertical stiffeners in plate girders are spaced not greater than", "opta": "d", "optb": "1.25 d", "optc": "1.5 d", "optd": "1.75 d", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the unsupported length of a stanchion is 4 metres and least radius of gyration of its cross-section is 5, the slenderness ratio of the stanchion, is", "opta": "60", "optb": "70", "optc": "80", "optd": "90", "opte": "100", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The area Ap of cover plates in one flange of a built up beam, is given by", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The average shear stress for rolled steel beam section, is", "opta": "845 kg/cm2", "optb": "945 kg/cm2", "optc": "1025 kg/cm2", "optd": "1500 kg/cm2", "opte": "1875 kg/cm2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a rectangular section, the ratio of the maximum and average shear stresses, is", "opta": "1.5", "optb": "2.0", "optc": "2.5", "optd": "3.0", "opte": "4.0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To keep the intensity of bearing pressure between the column base and concrete compressive and to vary from zero to , the ratio of the moment M to the axial load P should be", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cross-section of a standard fillet is a triangle whose base angles are", "opta": "45\u00b0 and 45\u00b0", "optb": "30\u00b0 and 60\u00b0", "optc": "40\u00b0 and 50\u00b0", "optd": "20\u00b0 and 70\u00b0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Secant formula for direct stress in compression, is applicable only for slenderness ratio upto", "opta": "120", "optb": "130", "optc": "140", "optd": "150", "opte": "160", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A second horizontal stiffener is always placed at the neutral axis of the girder if the thickness of the web is less than", "opta": "d/250 for structural steel", "optb": "d/225 for high tensile steel", "optc": "both (c) and (b)", "optd": "neither (a) nor (b)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The rolled steel I-sections are most commonly used as beams because these provide", "opta": "large moment of inertia with less cross-sectional area", "optb": "large moment of resistance as compared to other section", "optc": "greater lateral stability", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The thickness t of a single flat lacing should not be less than", "opta": "1/30 th length between inner end rivets", "optb": "1/40 th length between inner end rivets", "optc": "1/50 th length between inner end rivets", "optd": "1/60 th length between inner end rivets", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the steel member exposed to weather and accessible for repainting, the thickness of steel should not be less than (excepting the webs of Indian Standard rolled steel joists and channels).", "opta": "4 mm", "optb": "6 mm", "optc": "8 mm", "optd": "10 mm", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The permissible stress in bending for rolled steel I-beams and channels, is", "opta": "1500 kg/cm2", "optb": "1575 kg/cm2", "optc": "945 kg/cm2", "optd": "1650 kg/cm2", "opte": "1875 kg/cm2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Column footing is provided", "opta": "to spread the column load over a larger area", "optb": "to ensure that intensity of bearing pressure between the column footing and soil does not exceed permissible bearing capacity of the soil", "optc": "to distribute the column load over soil through the column footing", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "When the gauge distance is larger than the pitch, the failure of the section may occur in a zig-zag line", "optb": "When the gauge distance is smaller than the pitch, the failure of the section may occur in a straight right angle section through the centre of rivet holes", "optc": "When the gauge distance and pitch are both equal, the failure to the section becomes more likely as the diameter of the holes increases", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The ratio of longitudinal stress to strain within eiastic limit, is known as", "opta": "modulus of elasticity", "optb": "shear modulus of elasticity", "optc": "bulk modulus of elasticity", "optd": "tangent modulus of elasticity", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If flexural rigidity of a column whose length is L and the loaded end is free, is El, the critical load will be", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a column of height L fixed in position and direction both at its top and bottom, its effective length, is", "opta": "L", "optb": "L", "optc": "(1/2)*L", "optd": "2L", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a tension member if b is width of plate, t is thickness of plate, p is staggered pitch, g is gauge distance, n is number of rivet holes in zig-zag line, n is number of gauge spaces, d is gross diameter of rivets, then the net sectional area Anet of the plate, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Net sectional area of a tension member, is equal to its gross section area", "opta": "plus the area of the rivet holes", "optb": "divided by the area of rivet holes", "optc": "multiplied by the area of the rivet holes", "optd": "minus the area of the rivet holes", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The distance measured along one rivet line from the centre of a rivet to the centre of adjoining rivet on an adjacent parallel rivet line, is called", "opta": "pitch of rivet", "optb": "gauge distance of rivet", "optc": "staggered pitch", "optd": "all the above", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Tongue plates are provided in a steel girder at", "opta": "the upper flange", "optb": "the lower flange", "optc": "the upper end of the web", "optd": "the lower end of the web", "opte": "the upper and lower ends of the web.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}